Privacy Policy
==============

Foundation Consumer Healthcare, LLC respects and values your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we handle the personal information that you provide to us on Web Sites controlled by Foundation Consumer Healthcare, LLC and its affiliated companies (collectively, “Foundation,” “us” or “we”), which link to this Privacy Policy and include, for example, www.foundationconsumerhealthcare.com (collectively, “Foundation Sites”). Unless otherwise specifically noted, this Privacy Policy does not apply to personal information collected from you offline, to Foundation Web Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy, to residents of countries other than the United States, or to third-party Web Sites to which the Foundation Sites or other Foundation Web Sites may link. Foundation is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party Web Sites and you should make your own inquiries regarding them. Your use of Foundation Sites is subject to this Privacy Policy and the relevant terms, conditions and disclaimers for that particular site (“Terms of Use”).

By using the Foundation Site, you agree to our collecting and using your personal information in the manner described in this Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy before using Foundation Sites or submitting personal information to us.

### How does this Privacy Policy define “personal information”?

“Personal information” means information that identifies you or could reasonably be used to identify you and which is submitted to and/or collected by the Foundation Sites and maintained by Foundation in an accessible form. Examples of personal information include your name, your postal address and your telephone number.

### How does Foundation collect information online?

Foundation collects information in two ways:

1. Personal Information You Submit:Foundation collects personal information that you enter into data fields on Foundation Sites. For example, you may submit your name, postal address, e-mail address, and/or other information in order to receive information about various subjects, register for Foundation programs, contact Foundation customer service, or respond to Foundation surveys. To protect your privacy, you should not provide Foundation with any information that is not specifically requested, such as your medical history.
2. Passive Collection of Unidentifiable Information:The Foundation Sites may collect information about your visits to such sites without you actively submitting such information. Unidentifiable information may be collected using various technologies, such as cookies, Internet tags, and Web beacons. Your Internet browser automatically transmits to Foundation Sites some of this unidentifiable information, such as the URL of the Web Site you just visited and the browser version your computer is operating. Passive information collection technologies can make your use of Foundation Sites easier by allowing Foundation to provide better service, customize sites based on consumer preferences, compile statistics, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve the Foundation Sites. Certain features of Foundation Sites may not work without use of passive information collection technologies. Information collected by these technologies cannot be used to identity you without additional identifiable information.

### In what circumstances might Foundation collect and use personal information?

Foundation will use the personal information you provide through Foundation Sites to respond to your questions and to provide you with efficient customer service. After you have entered personal information into a form or data field on a Foundation Site, Foundation may use certain identifying technologies to allow that Foundation Site to “remember” your personal preferences, such as sections of that Foundation Site that you visit frequently and, if you choose, your user ID. We may also use this personal information for other business purposes, such as to offer you the opportunity to receive notices regarding Foundation’s products or services, to invite you to participate in surveys about our products, or to notify you about special promotions.

### Will Foundation combine personal information I provide on a Foundation Site with other personal information about me?

Foundation may combine the personal information that a customer provides on one Foundation website with the personal information provided by that customer on other Foundation Sites. Foundation may combine personal information that you provide to us online with our offline records. Foundation may combine personal information that you have provided to us directly with records provided by third parties. We use this consolidated information to help us better design Foundation Sites and Foundation products, to communicate information to you, to enhance our marketing and research activities, and to facilitate other business functions.

### Does Foundation consolidate personal information?

Foundation may consolidate the personal information of patrons who use Foundation Sites. We use this information to help us better design Foundation Sites and Foundation products, to communicate information to you, to enhance our marketing and research activities, and to facilitate other business functions.

### What choices do I have about how Foundation collects and use personal information about me?

You may always limit the amount and type of personal information that Foundation and any affiliated sponsors receive about you by choosing not to enter any personal information into forms or data fields on Foundation Sites. Some of our online services can only be provided to you if you provide us with appropriate personal information. Other parts of Foundation Sites may ask whether you wish to opt out or opt into our contact lists for offers, promotions and additional services that may be of interest to you.

You may also be provided with preference questions or preference boxes allowing you to indicate that you do not want Foundation Sites to use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to “remember” your personal information, such as user IDs or mailing addresses, on return visits. However, Foundation Sites that use tracking technologies to collect unidentifiable information do not generally provide you with the ability to opt out of the tracking technologies. Some Internet browsers allow you to limit or disable the use of tracking technologies that collect unidentifiable information.

### Why do Foundation Sites use “cookies” and other tracking technologies?

A “cookie” is a file that our webserver may send to your computer when you access a Foundation Site. This file is then stored on your computer. After you have entered personal information into a form or data field on a Foundation Site, Foundation may use cookies and certain other technologies to allow that website to “remember” your personal preferences, such as sections of that website that you visit frequently and, if you choose, your user ID. Passive information collection technologies can make your use of Foundation Sites easier by allowing Foundation to provide better service, customize sites based on consumer preferences, compile statistics, analyze trends, and otherwise administer and improve Foundation Sites. Certain features of Foundation Sites may not work without use of passive information collection technologies. You can also learn more about cookies by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org.

### What types of cookies and other tracking technologies do Foundation Sites use?

The Foundation Sites may use “session” cookies: Session cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your web browser window or otherwise turn your computer off. Session cookies are used, for example, to improve navigation on our websites, block visitors from providing information where inappropriate (the site “remembers” previous entries of age or country of origin that were outside the specified parameters and blocks subsequent changes), and to collect aggregated statistical information.

The Foundation Sites may use “persistent” cookies: Persistent cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of purposes, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (e.g., passwords), helping to determine what areas of the web site visitors find most valuable, and customizing the web site based on your preferences on an ongoing basis. Persistent cookies placed by this site on your computer may hold personally identifiable information, but only if you have registered or have otherwise consented to the retention of personally identifiable information you have provided at the site. Otherwise, our site’s server only knows that an unidentified visitor with your cookies has returned to the site.

The Foundation Sites may use “web beacons” (also known as internet tags, single-pixel GIFs, clear GIFs, and invisible GIFs): A web beacon is a tiny graphic on a web page or in an email message that is used to track pages viewed or messages opened. Web beacons tell the website server information such as the IP address and browser type related to the visitor’s computer. Web beacons may be placed on online advertisements that bring people to our site and on different pages of our site. Web beacons provide us with information on how many times a page is opened and which information is consulted.

### What choices do I have about Foundation’s use of cookies and other tracking technologies?

You can choose to enable or disable the use of cookies and other tracking technologies on the Foundation Sites. Exactly how these choices are presented to you and the process for making such choices may vary by website.

On some Foundation Sites, you may be asked to explicitly consent to the use of cookies and/or other tracking technologies on that web site. Cookies that are necessary to the operation of the site and to the provision of the services you have requested will continue to function regardless of whether you have provided consent. Other types of cookies and tracking technologies will be turned off until you provide explicit consent. As a result, the functionality of the site may be reduced until you choose to provide explicit consent.

On some Foundation Sites, you may be provided with preference questions or boxes allowing you to indicate that you do not want that website to use cookies or other tracking technologies that are not necessary to the operation of the site. If you choose to exercise this opt-out option, the functionality of the site may be reduced as a result.

Some Internet browsers allow you to limit or disable the use of cookies and other tracking technologies. Please refer to the information provided by your Internet browser for instructions on how to do so (generally found under a “Help” menu).

### Who will have access to personal information about me?

Personal information can be accessed by a restricted number of Foundation employees, by certain companies with which Foundation may conduct joint programs, and by individuals and entities with whom Foundation contracts to carry out business activities for Foundation. We train our employees about the importance of privacy and how to handle and manage customer data appropriately and securely. Also, it is Foundation’s practice to notify you if you are registering for a program that is conducted in conjunction with another company that may require access to your personal information. In addition, Foundation’s practice is to require its contractors to keep your personal information confidential and to use personal information only to perform functions for Foundation.

### Does Foundation share personal information with third parties?

As a general rule, Foundation does not share your personal information with third parties, unless it is necessary to conduct a joint program or to carry out a program or activity through a contractor. Where required by law, Foundation will not disclose your personal information to third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes, unless you have been provided with an opportunity to opt into or opt out of this disclosure. However, if Foundation sells one of its product lines or divisions, your personal information may be transferred to the buyer so that the buyer can continue to provide you with information and services. If Foundation provides your personal information to individuals and entities which assist us with our business activities, it is Foundation’s practice to require those individuals and entities to keep your personal information confidential and to use your personal information only to perform functions for Foundation. Foundation reserves the right to disclose your personal information to (a) fulfill a government request; (b) conform with the requirements of law or to comply with legal process served on us; (c) protect or defend our legal rights or property, the Foundation Sites or their users, or third party licensors of any material on the Foundation Sites; or (d) in an emergency to protect national security or the health or safety of the users of the Foundation Sites or the general public.

### How does Foundation secure personal information?

It is Foundation’s practice to secure each web page that collects personal information; however, the confidentiality of personal information transmitted over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. We urge you to please be careful and responsible whenever you are online and exercise caution when transmitting personal information over the Internet, especially personal information related to your health. Foundation cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not gain access to your personal information; therefore, when submitting personal information to Foundation Sites, you must weigh both the benefits and the risks.

### How does Foundation protect the privacy of children?

Foundation does not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children (we define “children” as minors younger than 13) on the Foundation Sites. We do not knowingly allow children to order our products, communicate with us, or use any of our online services. If you are a parent and become aware that your child has provided us with information, please contact us using one of the methods specified below, and we will work with you to address this issue.

### What else should you know about your privacy?

Your use of any Foundation Site, including any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Use for that Foundation Site and all dispute resolution provisions therein, limitation on damages and choice of law. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you.

### How can I contact Foundation?

If you have questions about the use, amendment, or deletion of personal information that you have provided to us, or if you would like to opt out of future communications from a Foundation business or a particular Foundation program, please contact us by clicking on the Contact Us link on this Web Site or by e-mailing us at [contactus@foundationch.com](mailto:contactus@foundationch.com).

### How will I know whether Foundation has updated this policy?

Foundation reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy without prior notice to reflect technological advancements, legal and regulatory changes and good business practices. If Foundation changes its privacy practices, a new Privacy Policy will reflect those changes and the effective date of the revised Privacy Policy will be set forth in this paragraph. This Privacy Policy was last updated in February 2015 and is effective as of that date.

PRIVACY STATEMENT

Foundation Consumer Healthcare, LLC respects and values your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we handle the personal information that you provide to us on Web Sites controlled by Foundation Consumer Healthcare, LLC...

FOUNDATION CONSUMER HEALTHCARE

Copyright © 2024 | All rights reserved
